SECOND-YEAR PH.D. STUDENT · NATIONAL TAIWAN UNIVERSITY

Taipei. Taiwan

☑ dcml0714@gmail.com | 🄏 d223302.github.io/ | 💆 @dcml0714 | 📚 Cheng-Han, Chiang

### About me\_

I am a second-year Ph.D. student at National Taiwan University in Taipei, Taiwan. I am a member of the Speech Processing and Machine Learning (SPML) Lab, and I am very lucky to be advised by Prof. Hung-yi Lee. My main research interests broadly cover different aspects of natural language processing (NLP), mainly involving self-supervised learning, interpretability and analysis of NLP Models, adversarial attacks, and human evaluation.

### **Education**

# National Taiwan University (NTU) PH.D. STUDENT IN COMMUNICATION ENGINEERING

Taipei, Taiwan

Feb 2022 - Present

- · Advisor: Hung-yi Lee
- · Direct pursuit of the Ph.D. degree
- M.S student in Graduate Institute of Communication Engineering (GICE) at National Taiwan University from Sep. 2020 to Jan. 2022

#### **National Taiwan University (NTU)**

Taipei, Taiwan

B.S. IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

Sept 2016 - June 2020

### **Publications**

### **Conference Proceedings**

[1] A Closer Look into Automatic Evaluation Using Large Language Models

Cheng-Han Chiang, Hung-yi Lee

Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics: EMNLP 2023, 2023, Singapore

[2] Why We Should Report the Details in Subjective Evaluation of TTS More Rigorously

Cheng-Han Chiang, Wei-Ping Huang, Hung-yi Lee

Proc. Interspeech 2023, 2023, Dublin, Ireland

[3] Can Large Language Models Be an Alternative to Human Evaluation?

Cheng-Han Chiang, Hung-yi Lee

Proceedings of the 61th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 1: Long Papers), 2023, Toronto, Canada

[4] Are Synonym Substitution Attacks Really Synonym Substitution Attacks?

Cheng-Han Chiang, Hung-yi Lee

Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics: ACL 2023, 2023, Toronto, Canada

[5] Recent Advances in Pre-trained Language Models: Why Do They Work and How Do They Work

Cheng-Han Chiang, Yung-Sung Chuang, Hung-yi Lee

Proceedings of the 2nd Conference of the Asia-Pacific Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 12th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing: Tutorial Abstracts, 2022, Taipei

[6] On the transferability of pre-trained language models: A study from artificial datasets

Cheng-Han Chiang, Hung-yi Lee

Proceedings of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence, 2022

[7] Pretrained Language Model Embryology: The Birth of ALBERT

Cheng-Han Chiang, Sung-Feng Huang, Hung-yi Lee

Proceedings of the 2020 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP), 2020, Online

#### **Workshop Papers**

[8] Revealing the Blind Spot of Sentence Encoder Evaluation by HEROS

Cheng-Han Chiang, Yung-Sung Chuang, James Glass, Hung-yi Lee

Proceedings of the 8th Workshop on Representation Learning for NLP, 2023, Toronto, Canada

[9] Re-Examining Human Annotations for Interpretable NLP

Cheng-Han Chiang, Hung-yi Lee

Explainable Agency in Artificial Intelligence Workshop of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence, 2022

#### **Preprints**

[10] Understanding, Detecting, and Separating Out-of-Distribution Samples and Adversarial Samples in Text Classification

## **Professional Talks**

#### **CONFERENCE TUTORIALS**

ICASSP 2023 Rhodes Island, Greece

PARAMETER-EFFICIENT LEARNING FOR SPEECH AND LANGUAGE PROCESSING: ADAPTERS, PROMPTS, AND REPROGRAMMING

• Tutorial speaker for parameter-efficient learning in NLP

**AACI-LICNI P 2022** 

RECENT ADVANCES IN PRE-TRAINED LANGUAGE MODELS: WHY DO THEY WORK AND HOW DO THEY WORK

2022

- · Main organizer of the tutorial
- Tutorial website: https://d223302.github.io/AACL2022-Pretrain-Language-Model-Tutorial/
- Tutorial recordings: https://youtu.be/thr4-hgLhi8

### **Honors & Awards**

Google PhD Fellowship, Google 2023

2022 Elite Doctoral Scholarship, National Taiwan University Taipei, Taiwan

2021 Advanced Speech Technologies Scholarship, National Taiwan University Taipei, Taiwan

# **Teaching Assistants**

#### **Machine Learning 2023 Spring**

Instructor: Prof. Hung-yi Lee

Feb. 2023 - Jun. 2023 TEACHING ASSISTANT

• Gave a 2-hour lecture on diverse topics of large language models.

#### **Machine Learning 2022 Spring**

Instructor: Prof. Hung-yi Lee

TEACHING ASSISTANT Feb. 2022 - Jun. 2022

- Gave a 2-hour lecture on the recent advances in pre-trained language models. Video is available: https://youtu.be/NzElV8jTNmw
- Gave a 3-hour lecture on the adversarial attacks in NLP. Videos are available: https://youtu.be/68lwXWFzCmg and https://youtu.be/68lwXWFzCmg

#### **Machine Learning 2021 Spring**

Instructor: Prof. Hung-yi Lee

TEACHING ASSISTANT Feb. 2021 - Jun. 2021

• Bulit, designed, and maintained the course website: https://speech.ee.ntu.edu.tw/~hylee/ml/2021-spring.php

#### **Machine Learning 2020 Spring**

Instructor: Prof. Hung-yi Lee

TEACHING ASSISTANT • Gave a 2-hour lecture on graph neural network. Video is available: https://youtu.be/M9ht8vsVEw8

· Designed a homework on meta-learning

# **Deep Learning for Human Language Processing 2020 Spring**

Instructor: Prof. Hung-yi Lee

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Feb. 2020 - Jun. 2020

Feb. 2020 - Jun. 2020

• In charge of homework on voice conversion

# Research Experience\_

# Supervisor: Dr. Hung-yi Lee

Taipei, Taiwan

NTU Speech Processing and Machine Learning Lab.

August. 2020 - Present

- Analysis of self-supervised learning models in NLP [7, 6, 5]
- Adversarial attacks in NLP [10, 4]
- Human evaluations in NLP [9, 3, 2, 1]

# Work Experience \_\_\_

#### National Taiwan University Speech Lab.

Taipei, Taiwan

SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR AND NETWORK ADMINISTRATOR

Feb. 2021 - Jan. 2022

· Managed a Slurm-based system with 20 GPUs

# **Professional Activities**

PROGRAM COMMITTEE 2021-Present

- International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) 2023
- Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL) 2023
- European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL) 2023, 2024
- AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) 2023
- Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) 2022-2023
- International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR) 2022-2024
- Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP) –2021-2023

JOURNAL REVIEWER 2023-Present

• Transactions on Audio, Speech and Language Processing: 2023